stwater.co.uk 2006-09-23

# privacy policy : Severn Trent Water

Please read the following privacy policy carefully before continuing to use this site.

### Issue Date: February 2005  

## Data protection & privacy policy

**1  Introduction**   
1.1 In the following statements ‘We’ ‘Us’ and ‘Our’ refer to Severn Trent Water Ltd.   
1.2 We are committed to protecting your privacy and We therefore ask that you read this Policy before providing Us with any Personal Information.

**2  The Data Protection Act 1998**   
2.1 The Data Protection Act 1998 (the “Act”) came into force on 1st March 2000.  It contains safeguards to ensure that organisations handle personal information fairly and lawfully, and gives individuals important rights to access data held about themselves, and to have such data amended if found to be inaccurate.   
2.2 In order to operate successfully, We collect and use personal information about groups of people with whom We have had or may have dealings, including employees, suppliers and clients/customers.  In addition, We may occasionally be required by law to collect and use certain types of information to comply with the requirements of Government departments.   
2.3 We are required to notify the Information Commissioner of the types of personal data We process, including the purposes for the processing and to whom the data may be disclosed.      
2.4 The lawful and correct treatment of personal information is very important to Us in order for Us to maintain the confidence of those with whom We deal.   
2.5 Procedures are implemented to ensure that We process personal data fairly and lawfully, in accordance with the principles and requirements of the Act.  For more information about the Act and the role of the Information Commissioner, please refer to the Information Commissioner’s web site at [www.dataprotection.gov.uk](http://www.dataprotection.gov.uk/).

**3  Our Use of Personal Information**   
3.1 We and other organisations which assist us in providing services to you will use information about you (‘Personal Information’) to provide and enhance Our services to you and for purposes ancillary to this.  
3.2 If you need to provide Us with sensitive Personal Information (for example health information), you consent to Our processing of this information where necessary, for the purposes described above.  
3.3 We may need to search the files of credit reference agencies who will record the search.  We may share information about the way in which you conduct your account with other credit providers and credit reference agencies.  
3.4 We may share the information We hold about you with other reputable organisations.  
3.5 We or they may contact you by mail, telephone, e-mail, fax or other electronic means with offers of goods and services or other information which may be of interest to you.  By providing Us with details such as a fax number which enable Us to contact you in these ways, you consent to being contacted in that manner for these purposes.  
3.6 If you would prefer Us not to use your Personal Information for the purposes set out at paragraphs 3.4 and 3.5 above, please tick the appropriate box provided when your Personal Information is given to Us.  Remember that if you do We will not be able to notify you of special offers and promotions or provide you with other information which may be of interest to you. 

**4  When might We Disclose your Personal Information to Others?**   
4.1 We will not disclose your Personal Information to third parties not referred to above except in circumstances which are permitted by law, such as the following:  
(a) Where We are required to do so by courts of law or to comply with other legal obligations including accounting and taxation requirements  
(b) To detect and/or prevent crime  
(c) For credit reference purposes

**5  When might We transfer your Personal Information Abroad?  
**5.1 For the purposes described above, We may sometimes need to transfer your Personal Information to other countries.  Unless you inform Us to the contrary by contacting Us at the above address, your consent to the use of your Personal Information in terms of this Privacy Policy will also be taken as consent to transfer your Personal Information abroad.  
5.2 If We do perform such transfers We will ensure that the requirements of the Act in relation to foreign transfers are complied with.

**6  Monitoring  
**6.1 Please note that if you communicate with Us electronically, including by e-mail, telephone or fax, this communication may be randomly monitored or recorded to protect the interests of Our business and Our customers.  This includes for the purposes of maintaining high quality standards, crime detection and/or prevention and to ensure that Our employees comply with legal obligations and Our policies and procedures (including customer relations practices).

**7  Hyperlinks  
**7.1 We may provide hyperlinks from this web site (“the Site”) to web sites of other organisations.  Please note that different Terms & Conditions and privacy policies will apply to other web sites.

**8  What are Cookies and why might We use them?  
**8.1 A cookie is a piece of text which attaches to your hard drive and from which it can store and sometimes track information on how you make use of a web site.  Please note that the web sites to which the Site may be linked may make use of their own cookies to collect information from you.  
8.2 We may use cookies because they will store and recall data which you have previously provided on the Site and will save you from retyping that data every time you enter the Site.  We might also use the data gathered by cookies to improve the quality of the Site and Our services to you. For example, We might use cookies to gauge the number of people who make use of the Site and usage patterns.  
8.3 You may nevertheless prefer Us not to send you any cookies.  If this is the case, you can set your browser to automatically reject all cookies. It is also possible to set your browser to notify you if a cookie has been sent to you so that you can, at your option, accept or reject that particular cookie.

**9  External Information Sources  
**9.1 We may on occasion obtain Personal Information from external sources such as credit reference agencies and other organisations with which We are associated or with which We conduct business.

**10  Requests for access to Personal Information  
**10.1 We are happy, on request from you, to provide details of your Personal Information, including Personal Information which We have obtained from external sources. We may charge a small administration fee in relation to any requests for access to Personal Information. If you wish to request access to personal information, please write to the data protection adviser whose address you will find at the end of this privacy policy.

**11  Information Updates  
**11.1 Please help us to keep your Personal Information current and accurate by contacting us at the address given at the end of this privacy policy if you notice that your Personal Information is inaccurate and/or out-of-date.

**12  Security**   
12.1 When you enter data onto secure areas of the Site, a Secure Socket Layer (“SSL”) is initiated.  An SSL is a security device which ensures that any data which you enter into a secure area of the site is encrypted during transmission over the internet.  Encryption of data is where data is encoded so that it is not legible until such time as it is decoded by Us. Every endeavour will be made to ensure that your Personal Information cannot be accessed by unauthorised sources.

12.2 As you may be aware, no data transmission over the internet can ever be entirely secure.  As a result, while We will use reasonable endeavours to protect your Personal Information, We cannot guarantee the security of your Personal Information and the use of the Site (including any e-mail facilities) is at your own risk.

**13  Changes to this policy**   
13.1 We request that you refer to the Site on a regular basis to ensure that you are aware of our most recent policies (including this Privacy Policy) and Terms and Conditions of Use of the Site.

**14  Address for Correspondence  
**14.1 If you wish to advise Us of any changes to the Personal Information you have previously provided or notify Us that you no longer wish Us to use your Personal Information for the purposes set out at paragraphs 3.4 and 3.5  above, please write to:

The Company Data Protection Advisor  
Severn Trent Water Ltd  
2800 The Crescent  
Birmingham Business Park  
Birmingham  
B37 7YL

14.2 Alternatively, you can send an e-mail to [data.protection@severntrent.co.uk](mailto:data.protection@severntrent.co.uk).

APPENDIX – Example of opt in text to be used on data collection forms on [www.stwater.co.uk]()

“We, Severn Trent Ltd, will securely retain any details you may choose to provide to us. Please see our Data Protection and Privacy Policy.

The information collected on this form will be used by Severn Trent ltd for the following purpose(s): 

If you return this form Severn Trent Water, its associated companies and other reputable organisations may be able to make offers to you from time to time.

If you do not wish Us to share the information We hold about you with other reputable organisations, both inside and outside the EEA, in accordance with our Data Protection and Privacy Policy please tick this box. [  ] 

Remember that if you tick the box you will not be notified of special offers and promotions, or other information which may be of interest to you.”
